KAITLYN LANDMESSER

www.katelandmesser.github.io

♀ Washington, DC

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

West Virginia University

Awards

- Magna Cum Laude
- Upsilon Pi Epsilon
- PROMISE Scholar

SKILLS

Languages

Swift

Objective-C

Python

HTML/CSS

SQL

Versioning + Tools

Xcode

Git

Cocoapods

Carthage

Charles Proxy

Jira

Sketch

InVision

Firebase

Splunk

CI/CD

fastlane

Circle CI

Jenkins

OVERVIEW

I'm an iOS developer with over 7 years of experience combining my love of design and engineering to create iOS apps that are a delightful experience for the user and great for every engineer who works alongside me. I'm seeking a position remote or based in the Washington, DC area where I can grow not only my engineering skills, but mentorship and leadership, too.

EXPERIENCE

Senior iOS Developer

Rally Health (UnitedHealthcare) – Washington, DC – May 2019 to Present Building the Recover Patient and Provider iOS apps, part of a new platform which keeps patients connected to their doctors and nurses before and after a surgery.

- Worked as the senior developer on an agile team of 6 where I led development and delivery of multiple API driven features, including the patient's Daily Care plan.
- Created many reusable components, which are used throughout the apps and have reduced feature development time, including a universal color palette.
- Rewrote the Messaging feature using MVVM, reducing the lines of code from 2700 to 700 without producing any bugs as a result of the refactor.
- Achieved 80% automated test coverage by creating a paradigm for writing robust and elegant XCUI tests by adapting the Page pattern to our codebase.

Senior iOS Developer (Principal Associate)

Capital One - McLean, VA - March 2017 to May 2019

Developed features for Capital One's award winning banking app, with over 13 million users and a 99.7% crash-free rate.

- Wrote code in Swift and Objective-C for new features, legacy features, and reusable components in the same codebase with dozens of engineers.
- Acted as backup technical lead on an agile team by defining feature architecture, assigning tasks, providing feedback on pull requests, mentoring junior developers, and collaborating with designers and product owners.
- Improved and defined paradigms for writing test sets and corresponding automation for legacy features.
- Designed and developed architecture and UI/UX for multiple iterations of Capital One's mobile voice assistant proof of concept.

VOLUNTEER

iOS Community of Practice instructor

Rally Health

2019 - Present

Capital One Coder's mentor

Virginia Middle Schools 2017 - 2019

Women in STEM mentor

Montour High School 2015-2017

OTHER INTERESTS

- Running: Recently ran my first half marathon and am working toward a full.
- Photography: Go-to photographer for my friends and family.
 Most proud of shoot: my step sister's wedding.
- Writing (mostly science fiction):
 Published a short story in a WVU college text book, but dream of being published in Asimov's Science Fiction.

EXPERIENCE continued

iOS Developer

Industrial Scientific – Pittsburg, PA – May 2015 to February 2017

Developed iOS (Swift), Java, C#, and HTML software applications alongside a small, multidisciplinary team of engineers.

- Designed, documented, and led development on an iOS application to read data from a gas detector over Bluetooth and transmit it to iNet, Industrial Scientific's real-time safety monitoring platform.
- Wrote Java code for bug fixes and enhancements to the core server of iNet.
- Created complex SQL queries to extract historical data from iNet to answer customer questions and assist in multiple teams' analysis and research.

Software Engineering Intern

NASA IV&V - Fairmont, WV - May 2013 to June 2014

Worked with Engineers on NASA's Multi Purpose Crew Vehicle (MPCV) team to validate and verify the vehicle's flight software in preparation for the Exploration Flight Test-1 launch.

 Developed test cases and corresponding Python scripts that exercised flight software requirements and high-priority project risks with PLATO (Partition Level Application Test for Orion), a testing environment specific to MPCV.

Undergraduate Researcher & Teaching Assistant

WVU Lane Dept. of Computer Science – Morgantown, WV – 2013 & 2015

- Worked with a faculty led research team in writing technical grant proposals.
- Ran weekly office hours to assist student with homework. Graded test, quizzes, and Python programming assignments.

PROJECTS

LED Art

Swift App on Linux – 2019 to Present

A high tech, low resolution art project, with a Raspberry Pi, LED lights, and Swift.

- Designed and created (via soldering!) an 11 x 11 matrix of LEDs, connected to a Raspberry Pi running a Swift program to power input/output.
- Converts a given photograph to individual pixel colors to display on the matrix.

WVU Mobile

iOS App - Swift, Objective-C - 2014 to Present

A campus information app, providing news and events, dining hall menus, rapid-transit status, a map, and more to over 30,000 students.

- Maintained and rewritten since it was developed in 2014 as a senior design project.
- Data is pulled from REST APIs and RSS feeds.
- Currently being rewritten in Swift UI.